Johan CHAN

Email: johan.chan@outlook.fr

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/johan-chan/

GitHub: https://github.com/JConan



Professional Summary

After completing my last mission as a Production Engineer in May 2024, I decided to dedicate myself fully to web and mobile development. As a Fullstack Developer specialized in Svelte and SvelteKit, I have experimented with several frameworks such as React, Angular, and Vue before choosing Svelte for its efficiency and simplicity. My previous background in data integration (Tibco BusinessWorks) and DevOps production support has allowed me to develop a solid ability to tackle complex problems. Today, I apply this expertise to ambitious projects, with particular attention to application performance and quality.

Skills

- Framework: ReactJS, Sveltekit, CapacitorJS, DaisyUI
- Tibco Business works 5 / 6
- Javascript, Typescript, Java, Bash and Powershell scripting, HTML/CSS
- API Design, API management (Mashery)
- SQL, Data Modeling and data transformation (XML, JSON, YAML, CSV ...)

Education

SUPINFO, 2011

ReactJS, certification with Le reacteur 2021

Experience

10/2021 - 05/2024: Production Engineer, BNP Paribas CIB Montreuil

- Level 2 and 3 production support: incident management, analysis and resolution
- Infrastructure support: ordering and configuration of machine resources and connectivity (CFT, MQ)
- Application support: PGP/GPG encryption key management and SSL certificates, application configuration and deployment
- Collaborative tools: implementation of a collaborative stack for SSH server access (Terminal + Cygwin + ssh config and aliases)

11/2020 - 07/2021: SOA/ESB Developer (TIBCO), Allianz France

- Development and support of TIBCO BW 5 applications
- API specification in SWAGGER format for SOAP services APIfication

10/2016 - 10/2019: SOA/ESB Developer (TIBCO), UP Group

- TIBCO BW 5 application development: Implementation, documentation, administration and technical support
- REST API development with TIBCO Mashery: Design and management
- Monitoring tools: Implementation of a dashboard with Elastic Search stack (ELK) for API traffic monitoring

10/2015 - 08/2016: SOA/ESB Developer (TIBCO), BNP Paribas

- · Event-driven application design
- Use of TIBCO stack: Business Works 6, Streambase, Business Events, EMS
- · REST API design and implementation
- · Design and implementation of an API monitoring dashboard in Angular2
- · Scrum/Agile collaboration: documentation and progress presentations

01/2010 - 06/2015: SOA/ESB Developer (TIBCO), Sanofi Aventis

- TIBCO BW 5 application development: Implementation, documentation, administration and technical support
- Data transformation: Data integration in SOAP+XML / IDocs / Flat file formats
- Monitoring tools: dashboard development with jQuery/YUI3 + Oracle